Guide to the American Reactionary Political Ephemera. Collection 1939-1950
University of Chicago Library
American Reactionary Political Ephemera. Collection
1939-1950
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
This collection contains ephemera pertaining to American reactionary politics from 1939 to 1950. Included are newspaper clippings, flyers, pamphlets, postcards, newsletters, notes, and other similar pieces of ephemera covering topics such as anti-Semitism, communism, isolationism, nationalism, racism, fascism, and other issues related to ultraconservative social, religious, and economic movements.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Scope Note
This collection contains ephemera pertaining to American reactionary politics from 1939 to 1950. The bulk of the collection dates from 1944 to 1946. Included are newspaper clippings, flyers, pamphlets, postcards, newsletters, notes, and other similar pieces of ephemera covering topics such as anti-Semitism, communism, isolationism, nationalism, racism, fascism, and other issues related to ultraconservative social, religious, and economic movements. The collection contains ephemera produced by conservative and liberal individuals or groups. Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject or name.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Political Pamphlets. Collection
Subject Headings
Right-wing extremists--United States--History--20th century; Politics and culture--United States--History--20th century
INVENTORY
- America Preferred, Carl H. Mote, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Anderson, Charles J., Jr., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Anti-Semitism - Council for Democracy, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Anti-Semitism - "The Fourth Book of Ike," undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Anti-Semitism - Gentile Co-operative Association, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Anti-Semitism - National Committee Against Persecution of the Jews - Pamphlets, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Anti-Semitism - Newspaper clipping, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Anti-Semitism - "The Protestant," 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Business Men's Committee, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Catholicism, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chicago Committee to Defend America, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chicago Council Against Racial and Religious Discrimination - Postcard, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Chicago Tribune - Criticism, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Clippings - General, 1944 and undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Communism - American Women Against Communism, 1942-1943 and undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Communism - Rep. Fred E. Busbey, mailing, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Communism - Constitutional Educational League, Inc., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Communism - James J. Cusack, Alderman - Handbill, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Communism - Spiritual Mobilization, Inc., 1949 and undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Constitutional Americans - Postcard, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Evangelism, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Executives' Club of Chicago - Executives' Club News, 1939-1946 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Fascism, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Friends of Democracy, Inc. 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- General election, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Government form, satirical, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Isolationism - American Action, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Isolationism - America First Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Isolationism - American First Party, 1944 and undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Isolationism - American Nationalist Party, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Isolationism - American Nationalists Committee of Independent Voters, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Isolationism - Citizens USA Committee, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Isolationism - Committee of Veterans, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Isolationism - "Last Plea for Europe," Oswald Garrison Villard, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Isolationism - Lumbermens Mutual Casualty Company, Upton Close broadcasts, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Isolationism - Peace Now, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Isolationism - Smith, Gerald L. K., 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Women's League for Political Education, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Labor, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Miles, Captain Edward, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "Money," 1946 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Notes, General, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Racism - "An Appeal to Negro Womanhood," Eddene G. Graham, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Racism - Clippings, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Racism - "The Struggle Against 'Christian' Hatred in Detroit," Merrill Otis Bates, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Racism - White Circle League, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Racism - Woodlawn Property Owners' League, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- "We, the Mothers" - Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- World Government - American United for World Organization, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- World Government - Dumbarton Oaks Conference, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- World Government - Rep. Clare E. Hoffman speech, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- World Government - Newspaper clippings, 1945 and undated (Box 1, Folder 52)